あつは　なついな
Phew! Helter swelter!
大阪の方では猛暑のとき　こう言うらしいです
That's what they say in Osaka when a heat wave hits.
Jeez, it's hot.
あっちい　何で裏山なんかに
Why's he got us out here on the mountain at the back?
If he's looking for a pool, there's one at the main campus.
プールでしたら　本校舎にあるんですよね
But that's not in this direction, is it?
場所が違うようですが…
No.
渚君　この前すごかったらしいじゃん
Hey, Nagisa-kun,
I hear you really knocked 'em dead the other day.
見ときゃよかった　渚君の暗殺
I sure wish I could've seen that assassination of yours.
人間相手に通じても　この教室では意味がない
It might have worked against a human,
but in our classroom, that doesn't mean a thing.
Day in and day out, we try everything we can think of,
みんなも毎日のように何かしら試みているけど
あの先生には　いまだ決定的な暗殺ができていない
but we still haven't found a surefire way
to assassinate our teacher.
All right, we're here!
さあ　着きましたよ　ご覧あれ
Behold!
先生特製のＥ組専用プールです
A pool I made specially for the E Class!
よっしゃ
Woohoo!
それ
こういうことしてくれるから　うちの先生は
Then our teacher does stuff like this,
which makes him pretty hard to kill!
殺しづらい
楽しいけど　ちょっと憂鬱
It's fun, but a little depressing.
泳ぎは　苦手だし　水着は体のラインがはっきり出るし
I'm a terrible swimmer,
and this suit leaves nothing to the imagination.
大丈夫さ　茅野
Don't worry, Kayano.
その体も　いつかどこかで需要があるさ
I'm sure there's someone out there
who appreciates you for what you are.
うん　岡島君　二枚目面して盗撮カメラ用意すんのやめよっか
You know, Okajima-kun, the nice-guy routine
and pervy camera don't really go hand-in-hand.
渚…　あんた
Nagisa...
You...
男なのね
You're a boy!
いまさら
You just noticed?!
Can you blame us?
まあ　仕方ない
Kimura-kun! No running at the poolside!
木村君　プールサイドを走っちゃいけません
転んだら　危ないですよ
You could trip and hurt yourself!
す…すいません
Oh, s-sorry.
原さんに中村さん　潜水遊びはほどほどに
Hara-san, Nakamura-san!
Watch the breath-holding!
長く潜ると　溺れたかと心配します
If you stay under too long,
how will we know you haven't drowned?
岡島君のカメラも没収
Okajima-kun, I'm confiscating that camera!
Hazama-san, don't just read all day! Swim!
狭間さんも　本ばかり読んでないで　泳ぎなさい
こ…小うるせえ
Wh-What a fusspot.
いるよね　自分がつくったフィールドの中だと王様気分になっちゃう人
I've heard of these.
You know, people who act like royalty in their own domain.
うん　ありがたいのに　ありがたみが薄れちゃうよな
Yeah... It sorta puts a damper on all our gratitude.
景観選びから間取りまで　自然を生かした緻密な設計
My elaborate plan makes the most of the natural surroundings, from the scenery to the design.
皆さんには　整然と遊んでもらわなくては
It must be enjoyed in an orderly fashion!
Korosensei's Weak Point #22:
Super-strict about pool rules
Aw, don't be such a stick-in-the-mud, Korosensei!
固いこと言わないでよ　殺せんせー
Have a splash!
水　掛けちゃえ
What was that scream?
何　今の悲鳴…
業君　揺らさないで　水に落ちる　落ちる
Karma-kun! Stop that!
I'll fall in!
I'm going to fall! Do you hear me?!
落ちますて　落ちますがな　頼んます
I'll fall in! Please!
殺せんせー
Korosensei...
Don't tell me...
もしかして…
いや　別に泳ぐ気分じゃないだけだし
Oh, I just don't feel like swimming. That's all.
水中だと　触手がふやけて動けなくなるとか　そんなんないし
It's not like my tentacles get too swollen for me to move or anything.
せんせー…
He...
Korosensei's Weak Point #23:
Can't swim
泳げないんだ
He can't swim!
This might be his most promising weak point yet!
これは　今までで一番使える弱点かも
But what's with that kickboard of yours?
手に　ビート板持ってるし　てっきり泳ぐ気満々かと
I was sure you were gonna swim.
これはビート板じゃありません
This is not a kickboard!
It is a wafer!
ふ菓子です
おやつかよ
That's a snack?!
kiritsu rei lock on
Stand, bow, lock on!
起立
礼
ロックオン
kiritsu rei lock on
Stand, bow, lock on!
起立
礼
ロックオン
oh yeah
Oh yeah!
sensei target on
The target is our teacher!
せんせー
ターゲットオン
ポテンシャル高い
potential takai
We've got a lot of potential
hodo mendokusai
It's just that we're not trying
ほどめんどくさい
dropout mentality
We had that dropouts' mentality
总监...Maki
台本...小伍
ドロップアウト　メンタリティー
总监...Maki
台本...小伍
ドロップアウト　メンタリティー
总监...Maki
台本...小伍
ドロップアウト　メンタリティー
总监...Maki
台本...小伍
ドロップアウト　メンタリティー
hinichijou wo ryougashi
No matter the unusual situation we were in
总监...Maki
台本...小伍
ドロップアウト　メンタリティー
非日常を凌駕し
僕らはうたたね顔して
bokura wa utatatanegao shite
We pretended to doze off
knife kakushimotta
While holding on to a hidden knife
翻译...naga
校对...Maki
ナイフ隠し持った
翻译..naga
校对..Maki
ナイフ隠し持った
翻译..naga
校对..Maki
ナイフ隠し持った
翻译..naga
校对..Maki
ナイフ隠し持った
翻译..naga
校对..Maki
ナイフ隠し持った
翻译..naga
校对..Maki
ナイフ隠し持った
起立
kiritsu rei lock on
Stand, bow, lock on
礼
ロックオン
ほっとけば　きっと誰か　やってくれると
hottokeba kitto dareka yatte kureru to
Thinking someone would deal with you eventually
ほっとけば　きっと誰か　やってくれると
时间轴...K.K
BDRip...VCB-Studio
ほっとけば　きっと誰か　やってくれると
时间轴...K.K
BDRip...VCB-Studio
ほっとけば　きっと誰か　やってくれると
时间轴...K.K
BDRip...VCB-Studio
ほっとけば　きっと誰か　やってくれると
时间轴...K.K
BDRip...VCB-Studio
ほっとけば　きっと誰か　やってくれると
doko ka taningoto datta
We didn't really feel invested in the job
どこか　他人事だった
だけど
dakedo
But now
だけど
mister teacher oshiete mikansei na bokura
Teacher, teach us, we're still growing up
Mr.ティーチャー教えて　未完成の僕ら
あなたという不落のターゲット　撃抜けるでしょうか
anata to iu furaku no target uchinukeru deshou ka
Will we be able to shoot through an invincible target like you?
あなたという不落のターゲット　撃抜けるでしょうか
idomu tabi ni kanousei ga afureta
kiritsu rei lock on kiritsu rei lock on
Our chances soar each time we challenge you
Stand, bow, lock on! Stand, bow, lock on!
idomu tabi ni kanousei ga afureta
kiritsu rei lock on kiritsu rei lock on
挑む限り
可能性はハーフ＆ハーフ
mister teacher mite ite mayoi ooki bokura
Teacher, watch us, as we try to find a direction in life
Mr.ティーチャー見ていて　迷い多き僕ら
誰よりもあなたのために猛勉強中さ
dare yori mo anata no tame ni moubenkyouchuu sa
We're studying our ass off for you more than anybody else
誰よりもあなたのために猛勉強中さ
殺意だけが
satsui dake ga anata e no message
Only the bloodlust is our message to you
kiritsu rei lock on kiritsu rei lock on
Stand, bow, lock on! Stand, bow, lock on!
殺意だけが
あなたへのメッセージ
jiriki gachi de hongan iku yo
We'll make our dreams come true on our own for real
あなたへのメッセージ
自力　ガチで
本願　行くよ
レボリューション
revolution
A revolution!
oh yeah
Oh yeah!
レボリューション
sensei target on
The target is our teacher!
せんせー
ターゲットオン
Episode
Vision
Time
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 i.kamigami.org 及微博 @诸神字幕组
Whaddaya mean, you're glad your grades went up?!
んだと　成績上がってよかっただ
You wanna say that one more time, Muramatsu?
村松　てめえ　もう一遍言ってみろ
I-I mean, this is the highest I've ever gotten.
い…いや　過去最高の順位でよ
Study Cram
Pre-Exam Slithery
これというのもあのタコの開いた
Study Cram
Pre-Exam Slithery
It's all thanks to that octopus's
Pre-Exam Slithery Study Cram sessions—
Study Cram
Pre-Exam Slithery
「模試直前　放課後ヌルヌル強化学習」のおかげ…
Study Cram
Pre-Exam Slithery
てめえ　あの放課後ヌルヌル受けたのか
You mean you actually did that Slithery Study shit?!
い…いや…
Well, uh...
Even after we three swore we
wouldn't give him the time of day?
ヌルヌルなんざ　ばっくれようって３人で言ったべ
But there's a big difference
between slithery and non-slithery—
でも　ヌルヌルすんのとヌルヌルしないじゃ大違い…
ヌルヌルうるせえ
Enough with the "slithery"!
You just played both sides till you got the grades you wanted. Damn traitor!
成績欲しさにひよりやがって　裏切り者が
I don't like how everyone's fallin'
for that octopus hook, line, and sinker.
気に食わねえ　どいつもこいつもあのタコに取り込まれやがって
It just don't sit well with me.
居心地悪い
Are you serious, Korosensei?!
マジかよ　殺せんせー
It's just like the real thing!
まるで本物じゃねえか
The hell are you doing, Yoshida?
何してんだよ　吉田
Hey, Terasaka!
ああ　寺坂
この前　こいつとバイクの話で盛り上がっちまってよ
The two of us were talkin' motorcycles the other day,
since no one else in school is into 'em.
うちの学校　こういうの興味あるやついねえから
先生は大人な上に　漢字の「漢」と書いて　漢の中の漢
Not only am I a grown-up, I am also a man among men.
この手の趣味も一とおり　かじってます
I've been known to dabble in this kind of hobby.
Plus, this baby can hit three hundred kilometers an hour.
しかも　このバイク　最高時速３００キロ出るんですって
What I wouldn't give to ride the real thing one day!
先生　一度本物に乗ってみたいもんです
You kiddin'? It'd be faster just to pick it up and fly!
アホか　抱きかかえて飛んだ方が速えだろ
The hell, Terasaka? What was that for?!
何てことすんだよ　寺坂
謝ってやんなよ
You apologize right now!
大人な上に漢字の「漢」と書いて　漢の中の漢の殺せんせーが泣いてるよ
Korosensei's not just a grown-up, he's a man among men! And you made him cry!
そうだ　そうだ
Yeah, what she said!
You guys are just buzzin' like a bunch of bugs...
てめえら　虫みたいにブンブンうるせえな
Time for an extermination!
駆除してやんよ
What is this?!
何　これ
A bug bomb?
殺虫剤
Terasaka-kun! Pranks are pranks, but this is going too—
寺坂君　やんちゃするにも　限度ってものが…
触んじゃねえよ　モンスター
Don't touch me, monster.
You're beyond creepy—and so are all of you,
気持ち悪いんだよ
てめえも　モンスターに操られて仲良しこよしのてめえらも
getting' pulled into bein' all
buddy-buddy with a monster!
What's got you so bothered, hmm?
何がそんなに嫌なのかね
気に入らないなら　殺せばいいじゃん
If you don't like it, just kill him.
You're allowed to do that here, after all.
せっかくそれが許可されてる教室なのに
You tryin' to start somethin'?
てめえ　ケンカ売ってんのかよ
Fine by me! From day one, you've been—
上等だよ　だいたいてめえは最初っから…
Now, now, Terasaka.
駄目だってば　寺坂
If you want to fight, actions speak louder than words.
ケンカするなら　口より先に　手出さなきゃ
Lemme go!
放せ　くだらねえ
Buncha losers.
What's with him?
何なんだ　あいつ
Does he have to stir things up?
一緒に平和にやれないもんかな
A world in crisis, self-improvement in the name of assassination,
地球の危機とか　暗殺のための自分磨きとか
recovering from being left in the dust...
落ちこぼれからの脱出とか
Honestly, I don't give a damn about any of it.
正直なとこ　どうでもいい
I just wanna take it easy and live each day as it comes.
その日その日を楽して適当に生きたいだけだ
And that's why...
だから　俺は…
Well done.
ご苦労さま
Here's your 100,000-yen reward.
はい　報酬の１０万円
We got a lot of prep work done, thanks to you.
おかげで　効率よく準備ができた
Now, these guys I don't mind.
こっちの方が　居心地いいな
That octopus has a good nose on him.
何せあのタコは鼻が利く
That's why we needed someone on the inside, like you,
だから　君のような内部の人間に頼んだのさ
イトナの性能をフルに生かす舞台づくりを
to help us set the stage for Itona to really show his stuff.
Terasaka Ryouma, I understand all too well how you feel.
寺坂竜馬　私には君の気持ちがよく分かるよ
Just relax. Follow my plan to the letter,
安心しなさい　私の計画どおり動いてくれれば
and he'll be dead before you know it.
すぐにでも　やつを殺し　やつが来る前のＥ組に戻してあげよう
We'll put the E Class back to
the way it was before he came.
You...
お前は　あのクラスの赤髪のやつより弱い
You're weaker than that red-headed fellow,
馬力も体格もあいつより勝るのに
even though you've got more raw energy
and a better physique.
Do you know why I can tell?
なぜか分かるか
お前の目には　ビジョンがない
There's no vision in your eyes.
No will or way or want to win.
勝利への意志も手段も情熱もない
目の前の草を漠然と食ってるのろまな牛は
The slow-witted cow who
dimly chews the grass before it
牛を殺すビジョンを持ったオオカミには　勝てない
is no match for the wolf with a cow-killing vision.
Why, you little...
何なんだ　この野郎…
Now, now.
まあまあ
Tomorrow we act.
決行はあした　よろしく頼むよ
We're counting on you.
What's with all the crying over nothing?
何よ　さっきから　意味もなく涙流して
No, no...
いいえ　鼻なので　涙じゃなくて鼻水です
These are my nostrils.
Nostrils
I'm not crying. My nose is running.
These are my eyes.
目は　こっち
Eyes
What's the difference?!
紛らわしい
I've been feeling a little off since yesterday.
どうも　昨日から体の調子が少し変です
おお　寺坂君
Oh, Terasaka-kun!
I was worried you wouldn't come in today!
今日は登校しないのかと心配でした
The spray can you let loose in the classroom yesterday
昨日君が教室にまいたスプレー缶は　やつだけに効くスギ花粉みたいなものだ
was like a cedar-pollen allergen that works only on him.
It dulls the senses of tentacled lifeforms.
触手生物の感覚を鈍らす効果がある
そうした上で　誘い出せ
Now that you've done that, reel him in.
Hey, octopus.
おい　タコ
It's time we killed you for real.
そろそろ本気でぶっ殺してやんよ
Come to the pool after class.
放課後　プールへ来い
After all, I hear water's your weakness.
弱点なんだってな　水が
You all come help!
てめえらも　全員手伝え
俺がこいつを水ん中にたたき落としてやっからよ
I'll knock him smack into the water for you!
You haven't helped with anyone else's assassination, Terasaka.
寺坂　お前　ずっとみんなの暗殺には協力してこなかったよな
And now you're ordering us around
when it suits you?
それを　いきなりお前の都合で命令されて
You really think anyone's gonna jump at the chance to help you?
みんなが「はい　やります」って言うと思うか
Like I give a damn either way.
別にいいぜ　来なくても
Hell, I'd be happy to have the
ten-billion-yen prize all to myself.
そんときは　俺が賞金の１００億独り占めだ
What's his deal?
何なんだよ　あいつ
I can't keep up!
もう　正直　ついてけねえわ
Well, I'm not going.
私　行かない
同じく
Same.
Oh, let's all go!
みんな　行きましょうよ
Whoa, his snot's all hardened! We can't escape!
粘液に固められて　逃げられねえ
Terasaka-kun's all ready to assassinate me now!
せっかく　寺坂君が私をやる気になったんです
This is the perfect chance for everyone to kill and make up!
みんなで　一緒に暗殺して　気持ち良く仲直りです
まず　あんたが気持ち悪い
First of all: you are gross!
Terasaka-kun!
寺坂君
本気でやるつもりなの
Are you really going to kill him?
Well, geez, Nagisa.
んだ　渚　当たり前じゃねえか
'Course I am.
Then maybe you should tell everyone your plan of action.
だったら　ちゃんとみんなに具体的な計画話した方が…
Aw, shut it!
うるせえよ　弱くて群れるばっかのやつらが
You weaklings, always cowerin' together!
It ain't like you got a vision for really killing him!
本気で殺すビジョンもないくせによ
But I'm not like the rest of you.
俺はてめえらとは違う
I got a vision for killing him, all right... Easy as pie!
楽してやるビジョンを持ってんだよ
Terasaka-kun seemed confident enough in his plan,
寺坂君は　計画に自信を持ってる様子だった
but not in himself.
けど　自分に自信を持ってるようには見えなくて
しゃべる言葉も　何だか借り物のようで
Even his words sounded like someone else's.
The disjointedness of it all was unsettling.
ちぐはぐさに　胸騒ぎがした
Yeah, there we go!
よーし　そうだ
Everyone spread out in the pool, just like that!
そんな感じで　プール全体に散らばっとけ
Who does he think he is?
偉そうに
I have my doubts about this.
疑問だね　僕は
Do you even have what it takes to make another person swim?
君に　他人を泳がせる器量なんてあるのかい
Hey, Takebayashi, shut up and get in!
うるせえ　竹林　とっとと入れ
Terasaka's turned downright tyrannical.
すっかり　暴君だぜ　寺坂のやつ
Just like he was back in first and second year.
ああ　あれじゃ　１年２年のころと同じだ
Ah, I see.
なるほど　先生を水に落として　みんなに刺させる計画ですか
You'll knock me into the water
and have everyone stab me, yes?
Then tell me: how do you plan to do so?
それで　君はどうやって先生を落とすんです
That pistol won't make me move a single step.
ピストル１丁では　先生を一歩たりとも動かせませんよ
This is not a gun but a transmitter that will send us a signal.
これは銃ではなく　われわれに合図を送る発信器
Once everyone is standing by in the pool,
pull the trigger to alert us.
皆がプールでスタンバイしたら引き金を引いて　われわれに知らせるんだ
You ready for this, monster?
覚悟はできたか　モンスター
Of course I am. My nose has even stopped running.
もちろんできてます　鼻水も止まったし
I've always hated you.
Wanted more than anything for you to disappear.
ずっと　てめえが嫌いだったよ
消えてほしくてしょうがなかった
Yes, I know.
ええ　知ってます
この暗殺の後で　ゆっくり　２人で話しましょう
After this assassination, we'll have a nice, long talk.
You think you can get cocky with me?
なめやがって…　来い　イトナ
C'mon, Itona!
皆さん
My students!
We're being swept away!
流され…
You'll have to jump in and save them, Korosensei.
水に入って助けなきゃ　殺せんせー
No way...
嘘だろ　こんなこと　聞いてねえよ
You never told me about this!
この先は険しい岩場が　落下すれば死んでしまう
It's steep and rocky up ahead.
if they fall, they're done for!
In the time it takes him to be nice and save them,
気遣って助けてる間に　やつの触手はどんどん水を吸っていく
his tentacles are absorbing more and more water.
Mucus can protect them from a little water.
少しの水なら　粘液を出せば　防げるぞ
That's right, Itona.
そうだね　イトナ
He can use mucus to solidify the water around him
and tweak the permeation pressure.
周囲の水を粘液で固めて　浸透圧を調整できる
But he's all out of mucus.
しかし　やつの粘液は出尽くしている
What the hell?
何　これ
I-I didn't do anything!
俺は　何もしてねえ
It ain't like what he said.
話が違えよ
I was supposed to get Itona over here and push him in!
イトナを呼んで突き落とすって聞いてたのに…
Oh, I get it.
なるほどね
It wasn't your plan.
自分で立てた計画じゃなくて　まんまと操られてたってわけ
You were just being strung along.
Look, I'm tellin' ya, it's not my fault!
言っとくが　俺のせいじゃねえぞ
Blame the guy who put me up to it!
こんな計画やらす方が悪いんだ
He's the reason everyone got taken for a ride!
みんなが流されてったのも　全部やつらが悪い…
You're the one who got taken for a ride.
流されたのは　みんなじゃなくて　自分じゃん
If you've got time to go pointing fingers,
人のせいにする暇あったら　自分の頭で何したいか考えたら
try using it to figure out what you want to do here.
Last one!
彼で　最後
Long time no see, Korosensei.
久しぶりだね　殺せんせー
What you've sucked up there is no ordinary water.
ちなみに　君が吸ったのはただの水じゃない
It contains a substance that dulls tentacle movement.
触手の動きを弱める成分が入っている
With Terasaka-kun's help, everything went swimmingly.
寺坂君に手伝ってもらって　まんまとうまくいったね
Itona-kun...
イトナ君…
Come, brother.
さあ　兄さん　どっちが強いか　あらためて決めよう
A rematch to see who's stronger.
I thought I was strong.
俺は自分が強いと思っていた
I set my sights on the weak-looking ones and put them under my thumb.
弱そうなやつにターゲットを決めて　支配下に置く
That way I was sure to win.
それで　俺は楽勝だった
But at this school, that didn't fly.
だけど　この学校じゃ　その生き方は通じなかった
Hey, let's skip this next class
and hit the convenience store!
おい　次の授業サボって　コンビニ行こうぜ
No... I've got to prep for English next.
い…いや　次の英語の予習しないと
So skip once. What's the difference?
そんなもん　一回しなくても大差ねえよ
Whoa, a monkey threatening a human!
猿が　人間脅してらぁ
Huh?!
But at this school, that didn't fly.
だけど　この学校じゃ　その生き方は通じなかった
Look, Terasaka-kun... No one does that here.
寺坂君さ　うちの中学そういうことしてるやついないんだよね
Old Campus
Even the big, bad leader of the pack
どんなにがき大将が粋がっても
Old Campus
is a miserable weakling once he hits the E Class.
Ｅ組に落ちたら　無条件で弱者なんだから
Your grades put you dead last, right?
君　クラス成績びりだよね
I can't wait for the day when I get
to hurl a few stones at you in E Class!
楽しみだな　Ｅ組に落ちた君に　石拾って投げ付けられる日が
That's when I realized the cheap weapon
I'd been using had absolutely no effect here.
俺の持っていた安物の武器は　ここじゃ一切役立たないとこのとき悟った
In fact, it might never work again.
しかも　たぶんこれから一生そうなんだと
These guys working hard
toward their vision of the future
こいつらみたく　さきざきを見据えて努力するやつが
would undoubtedly grow up
to boss around directionless mooks like me.
大人になって　俺みたいな無計画のやつを支配するんだ
I landed in the outcast E Class and figured I could skate by alongside my fellow goal-free students,
落ちこぼれのＥ組に落ちて
同じような目的のない連中と楽に暮らせるって思ってたら　そこでも違った
but I was wrong once again.
That monster showed up out of nowhere
いきなり　モンスターがやって来て
and gave the class one huge-ass goal.
クラスにでかい目的を与えちまった
Left behind again, I wound up manipulated
and used by some calculating schmuck with a plan.
取り残された俺は　ここでも
目的があって　計算高いやつに操られて　使われてた
Dammit!
くそ
He's fast, and he hits hard!
速い　重い　前よりも　はるかに
Much harder than before!
We reduced the number of tentacles,
focusing power and speed in those remaining.
触手の数を減らし　その分　パワーとスピードを集中させた
They're easy enough for a child to control.
単純な子供でも　操りやすい
Is this for real?
マジかよ
Did it really take that little water to neutralize him?
あの程度の水のハンデは　何とかなるんじゃ…
It ain't just the water.
水だけのせいじゃねえ
Terasaka!
寺坂
He can't go all-out 'cause he just got finished savin' you all.
力を発揮できねえのは　お前らを助けたからよ
See? Look above him there.
見ろよ　タコの頭上
Whoa!
Token chubster Hara-san could fall at any second!
ぽっちゃりが売りの原さんが　今にも落ちそうだ
And to protect her and the others, Korosensei...
殺せんせー　原さんたちを守るために…
She's pretty heavy and fat, so this doesn't look good.
あいつ　ヘビーでふとましいから　危ねえぞ
We've got to help her!
助けないと
But how?!
どうやって
Wait a second... Don't tell me
they roped you into doing all this!
お前　ひょっとして　今回のこと全部やつらに操られてたのか
That's right.
ああ　そうだよ
Shortsighted guys like me
with no vision and no goals
目的もビジョンもねえ短絡的なやつは
are doomed to be played
by smart guys like them.
頭のいいやつらに操られる運命なんだよ
But you know... At least lemme
pick who gets to pull my strings.
だがよ　操られる相手ぐらいは選びてえ
I've had it up to here with those jokers,
やつらはこりごりだ　賞金持っていかれんのも　やっぱ気に入らねえ
and I sure don't like the idea of 'em
walkin' off with the prize.
So, Karma... Why don't you try controllin' me?
だから　業　てめえが俺を操ってみせろや
Gimme a strategy, fresh outta that shrewd noggin of yours!
その狡猾なおつむで　俺に作戦与えてみろ
I'll pull it off perfectly and save all of them!
完璧に実行して　あそこにいるのを助けてやらぁ
Fine by me, but can you even handle one of my plans?
いいけど　実行できんの　俺の作戦
It might be the death of you.
死ぬかもよ
Oh, I'll do it, all right.
やってやんよ　こちとら実績持ってる実行犯だぜ
I'm the perpetrator who gets results.
All right. Time for the kiling blow, Itona.
さーて　とどめにかかろう　イトナ
Hey!
寺坂君
Terasaka-kun?
You tricked me good!
よくも俺をだましてくれたな
Don't get so upset.
まあ　そう怒るなよ
All you did was get your classmates in trouble.
ちょっと　クラスメートを巻き込んじゃっただけじゃないか
Perfect for a fellow who didn't fit into the E Class like you.
Ｅ組で浮いてた君にとっちゃ　ちょうどいいだろう
Shut up! I ain't gonna forgive you for what you did!
うるせえ　てめえらは許さねえ
Itona! You and me, one on one!
イトナ　てめえ　俺とタイマンはれや
Stop that, Terasaka-kun!
やめなさい　寺坂君　君が勝てる相手じゃない
He's not someone you can win against!
Stay outta this, octopuff!
すっこんでろ　ふくれタコ
What a hero.
けなげだね
Shut him up, Itona.
黙らせろ　イトナ
Karma-kun!
業君
It's all right.
いいんだよ
Shiro's not out to kill us students.
あのシロは　俺たち生徒を殺すのが目的じゃない
And it's precisely because we're alive
that Korosensei's attention is divided.
生きているからこそ　殺せんせーの集中力をそげるんだ
Even Hara-san might look like she's in trouble,
原さんも　一見危険だけど　イトナの攻撃の的になることはないだろう
but Itona's attacks won't be aimed at her.
It's like I told Terasaka:
だから　寺坂にも言っといたよ
he'll hit you with a tentacle
hard enough to knock you out,
気絶する程度の触手は食らうけど
but that's as fast and as powerful as it'll get,
so hold on for dear life.
逆に言えば　スピードもパワーも　その程度
死ぬ気で　食らい付けって
You held up well!
よく耐えたね　イトナ　もう一発あげなさい
All right, Itona, give him another.
Terasaka's still wearing his shirt from yesterday.
寺坂のやつ　昨日と同じシャツのままなんだ
Which means it got a direct hit at point-blank range
ってことは　変なスプレーの成分を至近距離でたっぷり浴びたシャツだってことだ
from whatever was in that weird spray.
That's sure to have an effect on Itona.
イトナだって　ただで済むはずがない
で　イトナに　一瞬でも隙をつくれば
So, with that opening in his defenses...
our octopus has a chance to rescue Hara-san.
原さんは　タコが勝手に助けてくれる
Yoshida! Muramatsu!
吉田　村松
Gimme a real big one!
でけえの　頼むぜ
Seriously?
マジかよ
Sheesh.
ったく
His weak points are the same as Korosensei's, right?
殺せんせーと　弱点　一緒なんだよね
So all we have to do is give him a taste of his own medicine.
じゃあ　同じこと　やり返せばいいわけだ
よっしゃ
そら
You've absorbed a lot, I see.
だいぶ　吸っちゃったね
Your advantage is dwindling.
あんたらのハンデが少なくなった
で　どうすんの
So what now?
We don't want you to claim the prize money, for one.
俺らも　賞金持ってかれんの嫌だし
Plus, your plans almost got us all killed,
そもそも　みんなあんたの作戦で死にかけてるし
and Terasaka got all beat up in the process.
ついでに　寺坂もぼこられてるし
If you want to keep going,
まだ続けるなら　こっちも全力で水遊びさせてもらうけど
we're gonna have a hardcore splash party.
Well, you got us.
してやられたな　ここは引こう
We withdraw.
If we were to slaughter all these children,
この子らを皆殺しにしようものなら　反物質臓がどう暴走するか分からん
who knows how his antimatter organs would run amok.
Let's go, Itona.
帰るよ　イトナ
Well? Didn't you have fun with everyone?
どうです　みんなで楽しそうな学級でしょ
Why not join us for real this time?
そろそろ　ちゃんとクラスに来ませんか
Itona.
イトナ
We managed to drive 'em off.
何とか　追っ払えたな
Good thing we saved your life, eh, Korosensei?
よかったね　殺せんせー　私たちのおかげで命拾いして
Oh, I certainly appreciate it.
もちろん　感謝してます　まだまだ奥の手はありましたがね
I still had some tricks up my sleeve, though.
That reminds me, Terasaka-kun...
そういや　寺坂君　さっき　私のこと散々言ってたね
You said some harsh things
about me back there, as I recall.
So I'm heavy, am I? Fat?
ヘビーだとか　ふとましいとか
I-I was just objectively analyzin' the situation at hand!
いやいや…　あれは状況を客観的に分析してだな…
言い訳無用　動けるデブの恐ろしさ見せてあげるわよ
Keep your excuses!
I'll show you what an assassin-trained "fatty" can do!
You really are tactless, Terasaka.
ホント　無神経だよな　寺坂は
No wonder you let people take advantage of you.
そんなんだから　人の手のひらで転がされんだよ
Shut it, Karma!
うるせえ　業　てめえも高い所から見てんじゃねえよ
You don't get to sit up there talkin' down at me!
What?
Is this how you treat your boss?
何すんだよ　上司に向かって
誰が上司だ　触手を生身で受けさせるいかれた上司がどこにいる
My boss? Ha!
What kind of boss would make someone take a tentacle on the chin?
For a world-class slacker,
you sure scored a sweet part in all this!
だいたい　てめえはサボり魔のくせに　おいしい場面は持っていきやがって
I was just thinking the same thing.
それ　私も思ってた
Why not take this chance to sling a little mud?
この機会に　泥水も　たっぷり飲ませようか
Hey! Stop it!
Terasaka-kun's not cut out for
putting together plans from on high.
寺坂君は　高い所から計画を練るのに向いていない
His strengths come through where he's out in the field.
彼の良さは　現場でこそ　発揮されます
He makes himself and others shine with his
physical might and the ability to get things done.
体力と実行力で　自身も輝き　現場の皆も輝かせる
実行部隊として　成長が楽しみなアサシンです
I look forward to seeing him grow into an action-squad assassin.
Terasaka-kun's pretty violent,
but he's adjusted well to our class.
寺坂君が　かなり乱暴だけど　クラスになじんできた
We didn't show it, but Karma and I—
all of us, really—were pretty happy about that.
僕も業君もみんなも　そのことが内心ではうれしくて
So happy that we all overlooked it.
クラス全員が　そのときは見落としてたんだ
Bigger than water: Korosensei's greatest weak point of all.
水なんかよりもっと大きな　殺せんせーの最大の弱点を
太陽が射す　閉ざした瞼の裏側に赤い残像
The sun shines
taiyou ga sasu
On the back of my closed eyelids
tozashita mabuta no uragawa ni
I see red afterimages
akai zanzou
With a notebook and a pen in my leather bag
kawa no kaban ni nooto to pen wo
革の鞄に　ノートとペンを　さあ歩き出そう
I go for a walk
saa arukidasou
I keep drawing, but I can't get it to look pretty
kaitemo kaitemo kirei ni naranai
描いても描いても　綺麗にならない
My choice of colors is not to blame
eranda enogu ni tsumi wa nai
選んだ絵の具に　罪はない
I still remember the shooting star I saw last night
kinou no yonaka ni mita nagareboshi mada oboeteiru
昨日の夜中に見た流れ星　まだ覚えている
I was waiting for...
I was waiting for…
Hello shooting-star Hello shooting-star again
Hello, shooting star
Hello, shooting star, again
I was waiting
matteita yo
待っていたよ
夢を見るあの子はずっと
The girl of many dreams
yume wo miru ano ko wa zutto
ここにいるの　Ah　Ah
Is always here
koko ni iru no
あの日のまま　Ah　Ah
Just like you did that day
ano hi no mama
また光って
Shine again
mata hikatte
片岡さん　クロールの基本動作を確認しましょう
バタ足は足の股関節から動かし　蹴り上げるときは膝を伸ばします
腕は掌を少し外側に向けてかき始め　手で下へ水を押し切ってから
肩を回すようにして　前に戻します
次回　暗殺教室　期末の時間